# SEAN CABRERA

2092 Kuhio Ave #2405, Honolulu, HI 96815 | (719) 232-7326 | sean.cabrera@gmail.com

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a full stack software engineer with over 10 years of experience. As a front-end developer with a passion for creating slick and visually appealing User Interfaces, I have a wide range of experience with various JavaScript frameworks including React and AngularJS. I also have experience with creating backend REST and SOAP services in Java. In my current position, I am in a customer facing role as a field software engineer collaborating with Air Force officers to build web applications that are used by over 40 organizations in the Pacific Air Forces.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Polaris Alpha Hickam AFB, HI June 2017 – Present

### Field Software Engineer

- Developed a Situational Awareness & Decision Support web application, used heavily by Pacific Air Forces (PACAF) staff in both Real World and Exercise operational environments.
- Developed a SITREP Reporting web application used by over 40 organizations in PACAF.
- Implemented various web-based data visualizations including a Task Metrics dashboard, Posture chart, Battle Rhythm, SITREP rollup, and Crisis Prep gantt chart.
- Collaborated closely with Air Force customers on requirements for custom web applications and data visualizations
- Technologies utilized include JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, d3.js, OpenLayers 3, HTML, CSS, JSP, Java, SQL Server, JBoss, Google Earth.

Polaris Alpha Fort Shafter, HI September 2016 – June 2017

## Field Support Representative

- Supported customers in their usage of CIDNE, WebTAS and INDURE at the Asia Pacific Counter-IED Fusion Center (APCFC). Responsibilities included training, collecting requirements and troubleshooting.
- Increased the usage of WebTAS at the APCFC and adopted a new user base on INDURE.

Polaris Alpha Colorado Springs, CO June 2011 – September 2016 **Software Engineer** 

- Developed the front end for the Global Health Mapping Tool and Prison Rape Elimination Act Tracking System web applications with **AngularJS**, **JavaScript**, **Bootstrap**, **D3.js**, **Google Maps API**, **HTML and CSS** from the ground up.
- Developed new requirements for several Coast Guard WebTAS applications with **knockout.js**, **JavaScript**, **jQuery**, **HTML** and **CSS**.
- Developed new requirements for the Civil Aviation Knowledge Base web application built with **jQuery**, **JavaScript**, **HTML** and **CSS**.
- Developed the User Management feature for CIDNE 3.x with **backbone.js**, **jQuery**, **JavaScript**, **HTML** and **CSS**.
- Developed back end **REST** services for multiple web applications in **Java**.
- Developed back end **SOAP** services for the Joint Space Operations Mission System program in **Java and J2EE**.
- Developed **Java Swing** based user interfaces for the WebTAS and Civil Aviation Knowledge Base desktop applications.

Lockheed Martin IS&GS Colorado Springs, CO

April 2009 – June 2011

#### **Software Engineer**

Command, Control, Battle Management & Communications (C2BMC) Program

- Developed **Java** code for Wininst, the automated Windows Installation tool for the C2BMC system.
- Wrote **Korn shell** scripts to aid in the creation and validation of playback simulations.
- Tested functional requirements and system changes.

Simtek Corporation Colorado Springs, CO

May 2006 – January 2009

**Design Engineer** June 2007 – January 2009 **Engineering Intern** May 2006 – June 2007

- Developed the **firmware** for Simtek's nvSRAM and nvSRAM with RTC products. The firmware was written in Simtek's proprietary **assembly language**.
- Designed the hardware and verification for Simtek's 8-bit microcontroller and real time clock digital logic circuits embedded in their nvSRAM and nvSRAM with RTC products using Verilog HDL.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Master of Science in Computer Engineering** 

March 2009

Colorado Technical University,

**GPA 3.95** 

**Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering** 

May 2007

University of Colorado at Colorado Springs, GPA 3.14

#### **PROJECTS**

#### **Project Portfolio**

• A portfolio of personal projects demonstrating proficiency in **React**, **JavaScript** (**ES6**), **HTML**, **CSS**, **Android and Java**: https://seancabrera.github.io/portfolio/

#### **React Neighborhood Map**

 Developed a web application visualizing the top bars in Waikiki according to FourSquare with React, JavaScript, Material UI, HTML, CSS, Google Maps API and FourSquare API.

#### **Find the Spot Android Game**

• Wrote and published an Android game titled Find the Spot utilizing **Java**, **libGDX** and the **Android SDK**.

#### **CERTIFICATES / AWARDS**

- Udacity Front-End Web Developer Nanodegree (Feb 2019)
- Java Client Programming Certificate (Colorado Technical University)
- CompTIA Security+ (July 2016)
- Polaris Alpha Gold Star Award
- Two Lockheed Martin Spot Awards
- National Science Foundation Scholarship